I was bored
심심해서
so I turned it on.
켰어.
Unnies went to eat pork belly just now.
언니들은 지금 삼겹살 먹으러왔거든요.
But
근데
before eating pork belly
삼겹살 먹기 전에
as soon as it ended
끝나자마자
I ordered room service
룸서비스를 난 시켜 먹어 가지고
because I was hungry and already ate it.
배고파서 이미 시켜 먹어 버렸어.
I can't eat pork belly again.
삼겹살을 또 먹을 수가 없어.
I just can't.
원래요.
Here ta-da.
자 짜잔.
You see it.
봤어.
It's exactly what I ordered yesterday. Rib eye and
어제 시켜 먹은 거랑 똑같아요.리바이랑
gimbap, tteokbokki, and sundae and
김떡순이랑
I ordered a tart too. I guess it was good because I ate it with the unnies yesterday. Today by myself
그리고 타르트 시켜 먹었는데 어제언니들이랑 먹어서 맛있었나 봐. 오늘나 혼자
well
뭐 또
it's actually really good.
생각보다 그렇게까지맛있네.
The unnies just left. To eat pork belly.
언니들은 방금 갔어요. 삼겹살먹으러.
So
그래서
there's nothing I can do.
뭐 할 수가 없죠.
I can't invite them.
초대할 수가없어.
I didn't just wake up I ate and
자다 일어난 거 아니고 밥 먹고
turned this on.
켰어요.
Bare face again today.
오늘도 생얼.
Bare face every day.
매일매일 생얼.이
At this point Flover is probably more used to my bare face right?
정도면 이제 플러보다 생얼이 더익숙하겠다 그지?
But having makeup on is just too stuffy.
하지만 메이크업 하고 있는게 너무답답한 걸.
It's stuffy.
답답한 걸.
Today's TMI
오늘의 tmi
Yesterday we had two rib eyes right.
어제 리바이 우리 두 개 먹었잖아.
Two whole plates. But
두 접시나. 근데
I was so full from eating one plate so I could barely eat the gimbap, tteokbokki, and sundae.
저 한 접시 먹는게너무 배불렀어요. 그래서 김떡수는거의 못 먹었어.
Just eating one rib eye.
니바이 하나먹는데.
So I'm upset.
그래서 속상해.
It makes me feel bad that Mr. Tteok-soon is crying.
떡순 씨 운다고 크니까 미안하네.
Because I couldn't eat it.
못먹어져서.
I feel
되게
really bad.
미안하다.
Tell a story
썰풀
I have no stories to tell. What kind of stories are there? Our
풀 썰이 없어. 뭐 썰 어떤썰이 있을까? 우리
Which side is squishier?
어느 쪽이 더 말랑해?
I'm not squishy. Flover
난 안 말랑해. 블로
My cheeks aren't squishy.
내 불은 말랑하지 않아.
They're really bouncy.
되게탈랑탈랑.
What's the word? Firm.
뭐라지? 탄탄해.
They're alive.
살려있어.
Hayoung unnie is really squishy.
하영 언니가 진짜 말랑해요.
But I'm not squishy.
근데나는 말랑하진 않아.
Send voice messages often
음성 메시지 자주 보내
please.
줘.
I'll send them often.
자주보낼게.
Voice messages
음성 메시지
I think everyone likes them.
좋아하는 거 같아. 다들.
Since everyone seems to like them I'll try to send voice messages
다들 좋아해 주는 거 같아서 음성메시지
often if I can.
될 수 있으면은 자주보낼게요.
How's that?
어때?
Doesn't it really feel like a voice message right now?
되게 음성 메시지 하는 거 같지않아?
Since you like voice messages
음성 메시지 좋아하니까
You said you like voice messages
음성 메시지 좋아한다며
Today all the letters
오늘 플로버들이
Flover gave me I read them all
준 편지 다 읽었어
Really
진짜
my heart got all soft
마음이 물랑
squishy
말랑말랑
soft
멜랑
so
져 가지고
I turned this on
이렇게
like this. I was bored too.
폈어요. 심심하기도 하고.
I really
난 진짜
don't know why our Flovers are so cute. Really
우리 플로브들 왜 이렇게귀여운지 모르겠어. 진짜
every time I read a letter it's so cute
편집 볼 때마다 너무 귀여워서
really
진짜
I mean it.
그렇다니까요.
If it's too cute I just take a picture of it
막 사진 사진 찍어너무 귀여우면은
like get in my gallery kind of vibe
내 갤러리에 너 들어와라 약간 요런느낌
If it's really touching
너무 감동이 몽구나
or something like that
이런 거있으면은
I just save it
처장이나
Really so cute.
진짜 너무 귀여워.
So cute.
너무 귀여워.
Ah really
아, 진짜
reading letters
편지 보고
reading the letters
편지들
really makes me feel
보면은 진짜
like I raised you.
키운 거 같아.
Really everyone is
진짜 다
different but
다른데
everyone is so cute.
다 너무 귀여워.
You all have a different kind of cuteness.
다 다른 귀여움을 갖고 있어.
What's my favorite content? What favorite content is there?
스프 최 컨텐츠가 뭐냐고? 스프 최컨텐츠 뭐가 있지?
What was it? Favorite content
뭐했지? 스프체콘텐츠
Uh
어
I
나
when we had our housewarming
우리 집들이 왔을 때
Ah the amusement park was fun too but the amusement park was a bit
아 놀이 공원도 재밌었는데 놀이공원은 약간
how should I say it? It was a bit chaotic.
뭐라 해야 되지? 정신이조금 없었어.
While going uh
어 하다가
during filming it was a bit
촬영할 때 조금
ah
아
chaotic.
정신 없다.
That's how it was so
막 이랬어 가지고
I
내가
figured out when I find it hard having a lot of people
사람들이
and when I like having a lot of people around
많은 어떨 때 많은 거를 힘들어하고어떨 때 많은 걸 좋아하는지
I'm getting to know myself a little more now.
파악을했어. 이제 나에 대해서 조금 더알아가고 있어요.
For me
나는
if there's an awkwardly large number of people
사람들이 애매하게 많으면은
my energy
기가
feels like it just drains out
싹 빠져나가는 느낌이고
but if there's going to be a lot of people and there's just a ton
사람들이많을 거면 아예 많아 버리면
it feels like it drains less.
덜 빠져나가는 느낌인 거 같아요.
If there are a whole lot like at a concert
콘서트 같이 완전 많거나
or a ton like at an event I actually gain energy
하면행사처럼 막 이렇게 엄청 많으면오히려 에너지를 얻는데
but slightly
약간
you know
이제
when it's just a bit crowded and bustling. Like
복잡복짝거리는 거 있잖아요. 약간
here and there like this
여기저기 이렇게
You know what I mean right?
뭔 말인지 알지?
Like the feeling when going to a market
이제 시장 갔을 때 느낌은
it's a bit chaotic
약간 정신이
kinda
약간
like the switch for thoughts in my head just suddenly turns off.
머리에 생각이 갑자기 딱스위치가 딱 꺼져요.
Yeah.
음.
Like that.
이렇게.
Am I not doing selca vlogs these days? Selca
요즘은 셀록 안 하냐고? 셀로
I do them sometimes
가끔하긴 하는데
Sometimes I think ah I should upload this today and all
내가 가끔씩 아 이거오늘은 올려야지 하고 막 하는데
but then I forget later so I work hard on it in the morning and forget in the evening so I keep failing to send them.
이제뒤에 까먹어 가지고 아침에 열심히하고 저녁에 까먹어서 계속 못 보내고
Yeah.
있어.
Webtoons
웹툰
Ah it's been a while since I read webtoons. Everything
아 웹툰 안 본지 오래됐다. 다
I don't have a filter on.
필터 안 낀 거야.
No filter.
필터 없어.
That movie everyone's talking about
밴돈 그거 되게
People were talking about it a lot.
사람들이 많이 얘기하더라.
I
나 TV
know what happens when I turn on the TV? The
켜면은 뭔지 알아요? 그
TV
TV
shows trailers and stuff as soon as I turn it on so that's how I found out about it.
켜면은 예고픈 막 뜨는 거 그래서알게 됐어요.
But I think it'll be scary so I won't
근데 무서울 거 같아서 안
I don't think I can watch it.
못 볼 거같아.
About Hayoung unnie going on a show
아영님 나가는 거
An article came out.
기사가 떴더라.
I was wondering
나는
how do they know? Flover was like
어떻게 알고있지? 플로버가 막
what do we do
이거
about this? and stuff but
어떡하지? 막 이랬는데
an article was out I had no idea.
기사가떴더만 난 몰랐어.
The seniors took really good care of me.
선배님들이 엄청 잘 챙겨 주셨어요.
Ta-da. The seniors really did.
짠. 안전 선배님들이.
In the past
옛날에
I said
내가
I want to meet
국민 MC 보는
the national MCs
언젠가 꼭 국민 MC
for sure
분들을 꼭
someday.
보고 싶다고.
I'm in my 8th year 8th or 9th year
내가 8년차인데 8, 9년 차인데
but I've never
국민 MC
even seen the national MC seniors
선배님들을 한 번도 본 적이 없는게막
and I said I felt kind of skeptical about it
회의감이 든다 이렇게 얘기한 적있는데
but seeing them like this
이렇게
was such an honor.
봐서 너무 영광이었어.
Yeah.
응.
My grandma and grandpa will like it right?
우리 할머니 할아버지가 좋아하겠다그지?
World Cup
월드컵
When was the World Cup again?
월드컵이 언제였죠?
The 11th
11일
wasn't it?
아닌가?
Right?
그죠?
I can't watch on the 11th. I have filming
11일에 못 봐요. 그때촬량이
then.
있어.
I can't watch on the 12th either. I have filming.
12월도 못 봐요. 촬영했어요.
Did I get scolded for spoilers? No
스포 혼났냐고? 아니
they didn't mention it yesterday
언급 안 하던데어제
the staff members
스택분들이
Doing a group live with the unnies yesterday was really fun though we usually play like that anyway
어제 진짜 단체 라이브 하니까재밌더라 언니들이랑 근데 평소에그렇게 노는데
it's been a while
오랜만에
since we turned on a live so it was fun.
라이브 켜서하니까 재밌었어.
The five of us really
우리 다섯 명 진짜
a five-person cam would be crazy right?
진짜 오인캠은 심받겠다 그지?
I'll let you join our girls night often.
걸스나이트 할 때 자주 껴 줄게.
We don't have any overseas schedules
이제 또 해외 갈 일이 근데
recently or
최근이제
in the near future so
앞으로 가까이에는 없어 가지고
Are we pu-ha or pum-mi?
우리는 푸하냐고 품미하냐고
Just
그냥
both I guess.
둘 다지 뭐.
Hey
에이
now I'm more used to peumina.
이제는 품미나가 더 익숙해.
Flover you guys
플로버도 너무
don't have to
막
be too
너무 그거에 대해서
worried about that.
그러지 마.
When I see
보고 이렇게 가끔씩 그런
posts like that sometimes it upsets me.
글들보이면은 막 속상해.
Because it seems like Flover is really stressing over it. We're
플로버들이 막 신경 쓰는 거 같아가지고. 우리는
actually
진짜
more used to it now
이제는 그게 더 익숙하기도 한데
honestly.
사실.
Because we're just thankful they call us a lot. And recognize us
왜냐면은 그냥 많이 불러 주신 거에더 감사해요. 알아봐 주시고
like
막
they aren't using it with bad intentions
안 좋은 걸로 안 좋게 쓰고싶어서 쓰시는 거 아니니까
they all mean fromis_9
다들 프러미스이다
so they just say oh it's peumina
이런 느낌에서 와풍민하다 이렇게 하는 건데
so what does it matter
뭐 어때
the intention is what matters
의도가 중요하지
I just used dialect right
방금 사투를 썼지
the intention is what matters.
의도가 중요하지 하지.
It matters.
중요하지.
Right? Huh? I really can't use dialect I think. Right?
그제? 어? 난 진짜 사투리 못 쓰는거 같은데. 그지?
Ah I'm really bad at it.
아, 난 진짜 못해.
I want to be good at Jeolla dialect too.
나도 전라도 사줄 잘 쓰고 싶다.
Ah Jeolla-do.
아, 질라도요.
I think I'm really bad at it.
난 진짜 못 하는 거 같아.
You say I'm good.
잘한다고.
Ah I really can't. I
아 진짜 못해. 나는
and my friends are all
내 친구들도 다 이렇게
exactly the same as me. Our way of speaking
나랑똑같아요. 말투가
is not like that
전혀
at all. So we all
쓰질 않아.그래서 우리는 다
don't know how to use dialect.
차리를 쓰는지몰라.
Hey I'm a Seoul woman now.
야 이제 난 서울 여자지.
I've totally become a Seoulite.
서울 사람 다 됐지.
I'm a Seoul woman now.
이제는 서울여자지.
Right now
지금은
I'm in Hanoi so I'm a Hanoi woman.
하노이에 있으니까 한우이여자지.
Tomorrow I'm going to Korea so a Korean woman.
내일은 한국 가니까 한국 여자들.
Korean woman
한국 여자
then a Seoul woman
이제 서울 여자되고
and
그리고
totally cool right.
완전 멋있지.
I bought clothes.
옷 샀어.
I was holding out
진짜 옷을 안 산다고 이제
saying I wouldn't buy clothes
버티다가
but then I felt like I had to so I bought some.
이제는 사야겠다 싶어 가지고 샀어요.
Now when I go home there will be packages
이제 집 가면은 택배깡
just piled up at home.
집에 이렇게 막 쌓여 있을 거야.
Am I not sleepy? It's 10 o'clock here Flover
안 졸리냐고? 여기는 10시야.플루보
Over here
여기는
it's a very awake time. I am completely
되게 uke한 시간이에요.제일
fine
멀쩡에 나는
It's almost 1 o'clock for you. Interesting.
곧 1시야. 독특해.
You must be very sleepy.
많이 졸려.
Very
많이
Ouch ouch ouch that hurts.
아야 아야 아야 아프다.
I bumped my forehead.
오빠 박았어.
I bumped it so hard. Ah it hurts so much.
너무 존탁하게 박았어. 아 너무아프다.
Ah man
아씨
It really hurts.
너무 아픈데.
Here.
자.
I don't have contacts in right now.
지금 렌즈 안 꼈어.
I feel like a person in Lilliput.
소인국 사람이 된 거 같아.
I look absolutely giant.
완전 내가 커다해 보여.
Ruined.
망.
Ruined
망
Me
나
getting braces
교정할
my Flover would be against me getting braces right
내 플로브는 나 교정하는 거반대하겠지
These
이거이
bunny teeth
토끼 이각
these bunny
이 토끼
when I'm like this these bunny teeth
이러고 있을 때이 토끼가
flirting flirting
플러팅 플러팅
front teeth flirting
앞니 플러티
You want me to eye smile.
눈우해 달라고.
Mmh.
음.
You're asking if I'm smirking?
비 웃는 거냐니?
Am I smiling? Flover
웃 웃는 거야? 블로버
I only have 10% battery left now.
나 이제 배터리가 10%밖에 남지않았어.
I really
난 진짜
don't charge my phone much.
충전을 잘 안 하는 거 같아.
Having the charging cable plugged in is just
그 충전선 해 놓는게 너무
so uncomfortable. It's annoying.
불편해요.거슬려.
I'll just fill up 30 minutes and go.
딱 30분 채우고 가야지.
When I go on business trips I tend to use roaming.
출장 가면은 난 로밍하는 편.
eSIMs
이심
setting up eSIMs is just too annoying so
이심 막 설정하고 하는게 너무귀찮아 가지고
when I arrive
도착하면은
I call and
전화해서
just ask for roaming.
로밍해 주세요 하는 편이에요.
The official announcement is out? About when we're having a comeback
오피셜 떴다고? 우리 언제 컴백하는지
Lie?
거짓말?
Lie
거짓말
The date isn't out yet. Right?
날짜는 안 떴잖아. 그지?
Yeah.
응.
Well between the 1st and the 30th
뭐 1부터 30일
or 31st
31일
it'll be somewhere in between.
그 사이겠지뭐.
I don't know either. Specifically. I can't remember.
나도 몰라. 자세해요. 기억이안 난다.
I can't remember. When did we have our comeback?
기억이 안 나. 우리 언제 컴백했지?
When are we having a comeback?
언제 컴백하더라?
I don't know.
모르겠네.
April 17th
4월 17일
We're coming back next year. Us
내년에 건백해. 우리
Did we?
그랬었나?
If we come back next year all the Flovers
내년에 컴백하면은 플루버들 다
are going to come to the agency.
어센드 찾아올 거 같은데.
Hey
야
saying
이러면서
give them a comeback
컴백시켜
they'd probably be like that.
이럴 거 같은데.
But compared to yesterday
근데 어제랑
really the
진짜이
typing speed is different. Flover
타자 속도가다르다. 블로버
Yesterday was really easy to read
어제는 진짜 읽기편했는데
but now it's scrolling up so fast.
이제는 진짜 너무 후르륵올라가요.
You guys didn't watch mine yesterday did you.
어제 너희들 내 거 안 봤구나.
Caught you. Who was it?
들켰다. 누구냐?
Who was it?
누구냐?
Hmm?
응?
Yesterday
어제
you were watching through the other unnies' accounts.
다른 언니들 걸로 봤구만.
Forget it
됐어
forget it.
됐어.
Right now it's
지금은 이렇게
hard to
채팅 읽기가
read the chat
힘든데
but yesterday it was so easy to read.
어제는 그렇게 읽기가 쉽더라고.
Yeah.
응.
You're totally caught.
딱 걸렸어.
A show I want to go on when we come back is hmm
컴백 백하면 나가고 싶은 얘는음음
anywhere
어디든
but hmm
근데음
uh
어
our unnies are so good at variety shows lately
우리 언니들이 요즘 옛능을 너무잘해서
so if the unnies go on them
언니들이 나가는게 또
people will probably watch
사람들이 봐줄 거 같은
I'll just play hard with Flover
플로버질이랑 열심히 놀고
I don't have confidence if the unnies aren't next to me.
난 옆에 언니들이 없으면 자신감이
I lose confidence. I wish the unnies would
없어요. 자신감을 잃어. 언니들이 내옆에서 막
reliably protect me by my side.
든든히 지켜줬으면 좋겠어.
Our unnies
우리 언니들
I guess it's because I've lived as a maknae for so long.
내가 막내로 계속 살아서 그런가 봐.
I guess it's because I lived as a maknae.
막내로 살아서 그런가 봐.
Flover.
플로봐.
This is
이거는
I went on Knowing Bros and was so nervous.
나 아는 형님 가서 진짜 많이떨었거든요.
Really nervous. My variety show phobia got worse.
진짜 긴장. 예능 울렁증이 더진거야.
You know I have a phobia of variety shows. Flover.
나 예능 울렁증 있잖아. 불러버.
But now
근데 이제
I was debating if I should take a calming pill or not. Should I take it or not.
내가 이거 청시만을 먹어 마라. 진짜청시만을 먹어 마라.
Really
진짜
my face turned bright red
얼굴 새빨게져
and my words
가지고 말도
ah
아
So they took even better care of me. Because I
그래서 더 잘 챙겨 주셨어요. 내가
was
막
shaking like this.
막 이렇게 떨고 있으니까.
So Chaeyoung unnie worked really hard to cover for me
그래서 채용 언니가 엄청 열심히수습해 주고
ah you'll know when you see it.
아 보면 알 거야.
I really
내가 진짜
so this time
그래서 이번에
when I went on
나가서
wow what am I gonna do about my variety show phobia?
와 난 진짜 얘네 물렁증어떡하지?
I tremble too much.
너무 떨어.
Too much. Too much. I really
너무 떨어. 너무 떨어. 나는 진짜
just tremble when you say variety show.
예능이라고 하면 그냥 떨어요.
Big or small
뭐크든 작든
unless it's our own content
자컨이 아닌 이상
I think I tremble.
떠는 거 같아.
Like
막
when I go on Fun-staurant and stuff I tremble and get so nervous.
편스토랑이랑 이런데 갈 때도 막엄청 떨고 긴장하고.
Yeah.
음.
When we went on Mr. House Husband I trembled a lot too
우리 살림남 갔을 때도 엄청 떨었고
really
진짜
it probably wasn't obvious during Fun-staurant
그때 편랑 때 티는 안 났
but
건데
back then
그때
I was like
막
I had to read the script but while reading
그 멘트를 읽어야 되는데 멘트읽는데
I had to be like let's go watch this
뭐 이거 보러 가시죠 이렇게 해야되는데
uh
어이
let's go
이거
watch this
보러 가시죠
it ended up like that.
이렇게 된 거야.
My voice was trembling so much I asked to do it one more time
목소리가 너무떨려서 한 번만 다시 한다고
Let's go watch this. Like that. When I went to the Korean History one
이거 보러 가시죠. 이렇게 한국사 갈때도
I trembled too.
떨었어요.
I was so nervous. You know why?
긴장을 너무 했어. 왠지알아?
Uh because I didn't know when the teacher would ask a question
어, 쌤이 언제 질문할지모르니까 내가
that was
그거는
nerve-wracking in its own way.
그건 나름 대로 너무 떨리는거예요.
Still
그래도
the Korean History one
한국사는
I trembled a bit less because
좀 덜쩔었던게
I thought
웃겨
I don't have to be funny
웃기지 않아도 된다라는
that thought.
생각.
Because of that
때문에
I didn't tremble.
떨지 않았어요.
This was
이것은
a bit of lightheartedness and
약간의 유쾌함과
a proper
적당한
proper lightheartedness and
적당한유쾌함과
studying
공부
it was just that
이거라서
and my role
그리고 나의 역할이
didn't really need to be funny
막 재밌을 필요가 없었던
because it was that kind of role
역할이었어서
so with a really comfortable mind
되게 마음 편하게
the seniors
선매님들을
I went to learn from them but
배러 갔었는데
for other variety shows
다른 예능들은
I tremble like crazy even if it's just a minor role
그렇게 주가나도 갈듯 막 이렇게 떨고
It's not that I'm greedy for laughs
개그 욕심 있는게 아니라
it's just it's just
이게 이게
they still invited me on a variety show
그래도 불러 주셨는데 예능에서
so I just think I don't want to be a nuisance
이게 누를 끼치고 싶지 않다라는생각에
So
그래서
I'm worried about this Knowing Bros episode
이분 아는 형님 나 걱정돼
that day I
내가 그날
ah
아
really worried.
진짜 걱정.
right now
지금
talking about it is after Knowing Bros finished
얘기하는 거는 아형님끝나고든
I shouldn't do it now. Later if PD-nim
지금 하면 안 돼요. 나중에 비님이
does something at the broadcasting station what do I do you never know.
방송국에서 뭘 하면 어떡해 혹시모르잖아.
Got it.
알겠지.
But
근데
what did I say I didn't say anything really. But just
뭘 얘기했다고 그래 얘기한 건 없어.근데 그냥
my appearance hasn't even aired yet but
아직 나간게 나오지도않았는데 막
like this
이렇게
just by myself
혼자서 막
I might not even have any screen time but
내분량이 일도 없을 수도 있는데
me hyping it all up by myself like this
혼자이렇게 북치고 장구 치고 하는게
is too
너무
much you know.
그러잖아요.
But anyway after I finished
근데 아무튼 내가 그날
that day and went home
끝나고 나서집가 가지고
really
진짜
all my energy
온 기가
was completely drained and then I even had practice
이렇게 딱 나간 다음에그때 연습까지
back then. So I practiced
있었어요. 연습도 이제
with completely empty eyes
눈 텅 비어서 연습하고
did fittings
피팅하고
recorded and then when I went home
녹음하고 이제 집에 가서
and laid down
딱 누웠는데
I just looked at my bed and laid down
딱 침대를 보고 누웠는데
and wow was I too
와 내가 너무
nervous earlier
아까
by any chance
혹시
did I tremble and get too nervous
너무 떨어서 긴장해서
were my words too
말이 너무
Not at all
전혀 그런
did I by any chance
혹시 내가
speak too harshly or use a phrase
언행을 세게 있거나 누군가를 불편하게
that might have made someone uncomfortable?
할 만한 문장이 있었나?
Did I overdo it too much?
내가 너무 무리를 했나?
I had thoughts like that so
막 이런 생각에
I contacted
본부장님한테
the director
연락을
that day
그날
Director
본부장님
if I made a mistake
제가 혹시 실수가 있다면
did I make a mistake? By any chance
실수를했었나요? 혹시 그런
was there a word
혹시 문제가
or action
될만한 말이나
that could be
행동이나
a problem or did I
혹시 제가 너무
overdo it too much?
무리를 했을까요?
More than my actual personality
지금 제 성격보다
a lot of
꽤나 많은
I mean
그러니까
I can't remember.
생각이 안 나거든요.
My switch got turned off earlier because of my variety show phobia
제가 아까 예능울렁증 때문에 잠깐 스위치가 껴져꺼져서
so I can't remember anything at all but
전혀 생각이 안 나는데
by any chance
혹시
do you remember Director?
분부장님은 기억이 나시나요?
Uh
어
I was really like that.
진짜 막 그랬었어.
Really
진짜
I was like
내가
why did I overdo it so much?
왜 그렇게 무리를 했을까?
I mean
그까
others might not think I overdid it at all. It's just that compared to my usual personality
남들이 봤을때 전혀 무리가 아닐 수있어. 그냥 나는 그냥 내 평소성격과
and my usual tendencies
내 평소 성향상
doing things
이게
that I normally don't do itself
내가 평소에하지 않는 행동들을 하는 거 자체가
a bit much for me
약간 이게 되니까
so
약간
I wondered
내가
if I
너무
forced it too much
억지 무리를 했나
I kept having those thoughts.
이런 생각을 막 했었어요.
Because
왜냐면
who was it?
그 누구지?
You know my close friends. Those friends. My princess friends.
제 친한 친구들있잖아요. 그 친구들. 공주 친구들.
They
걔네들이
always mock me when I go on variety shows
제가 예능을 나가거나
or shoot YouTube videos
뭐 유튜브촬영들을
and things like that
나갔거나 하면은
they make fun of me a lot.
엄청 비웃거든요.
Asking why I
왜 이렇게
force it so much.
무리를 하냐고.
They say my eyes
진짜 눈이
when I go out on variety shows like that
그런 나갈 때 그런 예능나가서
my eyes
저기 눈이
have
그
that expression I always make when I'm forcing it.
제가 무리할 때 표정이 늘 있대요.
And they laugh at me so much for it.
그러면서 엄청 비웃거든요.
When I went on Mimiminu's
미미미누님
channel they said the same thing after watching that video.
채널 가서 찍었을 때 그 영상을보고도 그랬어요. 많이
Your energy
기가
looked really drained.
많이 힘 힘들어 보이더라.
So I said
내가
Oh no. It wasn't hard. They took really good care of me
어아니야. 힘들지 않았어. 진짜 잘챙겨 주셨어 이랬는데
But they said no not that
아니 그게 아니라
it's just
그냥
it was so obvious you were forcing it.
네가무리하는게 너무 보였어.
Yeah.
그래.
They even replay it in front of me
그러면서 막 그것 애들이 내 앞에서돌려보고
and tell me
내가
that's your forced expression right there. Like that
너의 무리하는 표정은저런 거야. 막 이렇게
they point it out.
알려줘.
It's not that
그
it looks hard but they say they can see my eyes starting to lose focus.
힘들다기보다는 약간 눈에 초점이나가기 시작하는게 보인대요.
They just space out like that
싹 이렇게 나간는데
but it's really fun.
근데 진짜 재밌어요.
Going on variety shows is really fun and I love it
전 예능 나가는거 진짜 재밌고 너무 좋은데
I love it so much
너무 좋은데
I'm so happy
너무 행복한데
so
너무
I want to go on them
나가서
and work hard to promote our team but
열심히 우리 팀을 알리고 하고싶은데
our unnies are just so good at it.
우리 언니들이 너무 잘해.
I think playing with Flovers like this is the most fun for me.
난 이렇게 플루버들이랑 노는게 제일재밌는 거 같아.
Our unnies are so funny too.
우리 언니도 너무 재밌어.
Anyway but
아무튼 근데
the seniors took really good care of me.
그래서 선배님들이 되게 잘 챙겨주셨다.
I was
내가
trembling so much from the very start
시작부터 너무 달달달
like this
이렇게 떨어 가지고
You know I don't usually sweat. Flover
내가 땀이 잘 안 나잖아요. 플로버
I was sweating.
땀이 나더라니까.
Cold sweat was
막 여기
dripping down my back like this
이제 등에서 막 이렇게 식은땀이 이렇게
just like that.
막 그러는 거예요.
Really
진짜
it was like that.
그랬었어요.
So now that I've told you this behind the scenes story
자, 이제 이런 비하인드를 알려줬으니까
later
나중에
when the Knowing Bros episode is out
아는 형님이 뜨면은
when the episode airs
회차가 나오면
you can watch it thinking
재밌게
wow Jiheon
백원이
is working
엄청
really
열심히
hard.
하는구나.
Will I even have screen time? Anyway
내분량이 있을까? 아무튼
the other people did so well too
다른 분들도 다 너무 잘하셔 가지고
Jiwon too
최원이도 그렇고
I don't really know about that but
그건 잘 모르겠지만
anyway
아무튼
stuck in the corner like this
구속탱이이렇게
going wow
와 이러고 있는를
please look at me
보면서
and find me
많이
cute.
귀여워해 주세요.
I clapped really hard too
박수도 열심히 치고
ah and laughed hard
아 열심히 웃고
but it was genuinely fun so I laughed really hard.
근데 진짜 재밌어서엄청 열심히 웃었어요.
Have fun
재밌게
Squishy baby butt cheeks
아군빵
To do that I don't have enough cheek fat.
하기에는 내가 볼살이 없어.